现在规范可以谈什么呢？
Now what can a specification talk about?
它可以描述
Well it can describe the relationships
在参数和方法的返回值之间。
between the parameters and the return value of the method.
但它不应该谈论局部变量
But it should never talk about local variables
或私有字段、方法类或其他实现
or private fields, the methods class, or other implementation
细节。
details.
很多东西是读者看不见的
A lot of those things are invisible to the reader
规格的。
of the spec.
特别是在Java中，方法的源代码
In Java in particular the source code of the method
对于规范的读者来说是不可用的，
is often unavailable to the reader of the spec,
因为Java doc工具提取这些规范注释
because the Java doc tool extracts these spec comments
从你的代码并呈现为HTML。
from your code and renders them as HTML.
所以请记住这是你
So keep in mind that this is the only part that you
应该在说明书里谈。
should talk about in the spec.
现在在测试中，我们讨论黑盒测试
Now in testing we talk about black box tests that
选择时只考虑规格，
are chosen with only the specification in mind,
以及根据知识选择的玻璃盒测试
and glass box tests that are chosen with knowledge
实际实现的
of the actual implementation, as discussed more
在测试读数中。
in the testing reading.
但需要注意的是，即使是玻璃盒测试也必须
But it's important to note that even glass box tests must
遵循规范。
follow the specification.
现在你的具体实现
Now your particular implementation
可能比规范要求的更可靠，
may have stronger guarantees than the spec calls for,
或者在规范未定义的情况下可能有特定的行为，
or it may have specific behavior where the spec is undefined,
但是您的测试用例不应该依赖于这种行为。
but your test cases should not count on that behavior.
测试用例必须遵守合同，
Tests cases must obey the contract,
就像其他客户一样。
just like every other client.
例如，假设你正在测试
So for example, suppose you're testing
这个发现的规格，和那个有点不同
this spec of Find, which is slightly different than the one
我们已经用了这么久。
we've used so far.
它说的是你正在寻找的价值
What it says is that the value that you're searching for
必须出现在阵列的某个地方，可能不止一次，
has to occur somewhere in the array, maybe more than once,
它返回某个索引i，该值出现在那里。
and it returns some index i, where that value occurs.
所以这个规范有一个很强的前提条件
So this spec has a strong precondition
需要找到val，它是一个相当弱的
val is required to be found, and it is a fairly weak
后置条件，即如果val出现
post-condition, in the sense that if val appears
不止一次规格说明什么都没说
more than once the spec says nothing
返回val的哪个特定索引。
about which particular index of val is returned.
现在即使你实现了find
Now even if you implemented find so that it always
返回最低的索引，即您的测试用例
returns the lowest index, your test case
不能假设这种特定的行为。
can't assume that specific behavior.
例如，如果我们的数组是这样的，
So for example, if our array is this,
只列出三个七，我们在找号码
just a list of three sevens, and we're looking for the number
其中有七个，我们不能编写一个需要它的测试用例
seven in it, we cannot write a test case that requires that
此查找返回此处的零索引。
this find return the zero index here.
相反，我们应该写得更笼统些
Instead we should write it more generally
如果我们取索引的find返回，
and say, well if we take the indexed find returns,
然后我们在数组中的索引处查找值，
and then we look up the value at that index in the array,
那必须和我们最初的价值一样
well that has to be the same as the value we originally
寻找。
searched for.
所以这允许find返回0或1或2。
So this allows find to return zero or one or two.
同样，即使您实现了
Similarly, even if you implemented
当val不在的时候，它会合理地抛出一个异常
find so that it sensibly throws an exception when val isn't
发现，而不是返回一些任意的误导性索引，
found, instead of returning some arbitrary misleading index,
换句话说，我们正在写一份调查报告
in other words we're writing a find that checks
它本身的前提是，你的测试不能假设这种行为
its own precondition, your test can't assume that behavior
因为找不到
because it can't call find in a way that
违反了这个先决条件。
violates that precondition.
不允许违反这个合同。
It's not allowed to break this contract.
那么玻璃盒测试什么
So then what does glass box testing even
意思是如果你不能超出规格？
mean if you're not allowed to go beyond the spec?
好吧，这意味着你试图找到新的测试用例
Well it means you're trying to find new test cases that
执行的不同部分，
exercise different parts of the implementation,
但仍在检查这些测试用例
but still checking those test cases
以独立于实现的方式。
in an implementation-independent way.
现在让我们考虑一下测试单元的规格。
Now let's think about testing units with respect to specs.
回想一下我们有一个网络搜索的例子
So recall we had an example of a web search
有三种方法一起工作。
that had three methods working together.
获取获取URL并生成字符串的网页；
Get Web Page that took a URL and produced the string;
提取需要字符串的单词，可能是网页，
Extract Words that takes a string, presumably a web page,
并返回一个单词列表；然后生成索引
and returns a list of words; and then MakeIndex
它接受一组URL并尝试
that takes overall a set of URLs and tries
构造将单词映射到URL集的索引。
to construct an index that maps words to sets of URLs.
在里面进行索引调用
And this make index calls within it
这两种方法，获取网页和提取单词。
these two methods, Get Web Page and Extract Words.
现在回到网络测试阅读中，我们讨论了单元
Now back in net testing reading we talked about unit
测试，我们应该写的想法
testing, the idea that we should write
单独测试程序的每个模块。
tests of each module of our program in isolation.
好的单元测试只关注一个规范。
Good unit test is focused on just a single specification.
我们的测试几乎总是依赖于Java库的规范
Our test will nearly always rely on the specs of Java library
在这些方法中调用的方法，
methods that are being called inside these methods,
但是我们编写的一个方法的单元测试
but a unit test for one method we've written
如果另一个方法失败了就不应该失败
shouldn't fail if a different method fails
以满足它的规格。
to satisfy it's spec.
正如我们在测试读数中看到的例子，
So as we saw in the example in the testing reading,
单词提取测试不应该
a test for extract words shouldn't
如果获取网页不满足其后置条件，则失败。
fail if Get Web Page doesn't satisfy it's postcondition.
因此，提取单词的测试不应该调用Get Web Page。
So the test for Extract Words should not call Get Web Page.
好的集成测试
Now good integration tests, tests
使用模块组合，
that use a combination of modules,
会确保我们不同的方法
will make sure that our different methods have
同事和实现者的兼容规范
compatible specifications that colleagues and implementers
以不同的方式传递返回
in different methods are passing returning
别人期望的价值观。
values the others expect.
集成测试不能取代系统化设计
The integration test cannot replace systematically-designed
单元测试。
unit tests.
例如，如果我们只调用test Extract Words
For example, if we only ever called test Extract Words
换句话说，通过调用MakeIndex，
by calling MakeIndex, in other words,
通过MakeIndex调用来测试提取单词，
test Extract Words by calling it through MakeIndex,
我们只在一个很小的地方测试
we'll only test it on a potentially small part
它的输入空间
of its input space, the inputs that
是Get网页的可能输出。
are possible outputs of Get Web Page.
这样我们就离开了藏匿虫子的地方
And in doing so we've left the place for bugs to hide
当我们，例如，提取
that are ready to jump out when we, for instance, take Extract
为了不同的目的
Words and try to reason for a different purpose
在我们计划的其他地方。
somewhere else in our program.
或者当Get Web Page开始返回编写的Web页面时
Or when Get Web Page starts returning web pages written
以新的格式，等等。
in a new format, and so forth.
我们真的想单独测试提取单词
We really want to test extract words in isolation
有很好的单元测试。
with a good unit test.
我们之前讨论过可变对象和不可变对象，
Now we previously discussed mutable vs. immutable objects,
但我们的技术规范还没有给我们
but our specs Find haven't given us
说明如何描述侧面的机会
a chance to illustrate how to describe the side
副作用是对不可变数据的更改。
effects, where a side effect is a change to immutable data.
这是个突变。
It's a mutation.
我们将如何描述那些在后条件
How are we going to describe those in the postcondition
一个规格？
of a specification?
这里有一个规范描述了
Well here's a specification that describes a method that
变异一个物体。
mutates an object.
这是一个方法，有两个列表，
This is a method at all, takes two lists,
列出一和二。
list one and list two.
我要先跳到后场，
And I'm going to jump ahead to the postcondition first,
它修改了列表一，它修改了列表一
it modifies list one, it mutates list one
将列表2的元素添加到列表的末尾。
by adding the elements of list two to the end of it.
然后返回布尔值
And then it returns Boolean, which
如果列表1已更改，则为true
is true if list one has been changed
因为这个电话。
as a result of the call.
这实际上是一个相当常见的模式
This is actually a fairly common pattern
您将在Java API中看到，它只是返回
you'll see in the Java API which is to just return
告诉你是否有任何变异
to this Boolean to tell you whether any mutation has
真的发生了。
actually occurred.
所以我们把这个，简化了一点，
So we've actually taken this, it's a little bit simplified,
从Java列表界面。
from the Java list interface.
现在如果我们看看先决条件，
Now if we look at the precondition,
我跳过了先决条件，它告诉我们
I skipped over the precondition, it tells us
如果你试图
that the behavior of the method if you attempt
如果list one和list
to add the elements of a list to itself, if list one and list
两个引用同一个列表对象，
two refer to the same list object,
如快照图所示，
as is shown over here in the snapshot diagram,
它是未定义的。
it's undefined.
那是在外面——这打破了先决条件。
That's outside-- that breaks the precondition.
你可以很容易地想象为什么？实施？]方法将
You can easily imagine why the [? implemented ?] method will
希望强制使用此构造。
want to impose this construct.
首先，不排除任何有用的应用程序
First, it's not like to rule out any useful application
方法。
of the method.
而且它更容易实现。
And it makes it easier to implement.
因为它允许一个简单的实现，其中
Because it allows for a simple implementation, in which you're
从列表2中一次取一个元素
just taking elements one at a time from list two
把它们加到列表中直到你
and adding them to list one until you
到列表二的末尾。
get to the end of list two.
现在这个简单实现的问题是，
Now the problem with that simple implementation,
如果两个列表都指向同一个列表对象，
if both lists point to the same list object,
你将继续添加元素
is that you will keep adding on elements
在列表一和列表二的末尾，
to the end of both list one and list two,
你永远到不了第二个名单的末尾。
you will never get to the end of list two.
两份名单都会继续增长
Both lists will just keep growing
不断成长。
and growing and growing.
所以这个快照图演示了这种行为。
So this snapshot diagram demonstrates that behavior.
所以这是一个简单的算法
So that's a simple algorithm will not
如果列表1和列表2是同一列表，则终止。
terminate if list one and list two are the same list.
或者说实际上，在Java中
Or practically speaking, in Java it
一旦此列表出现，将引发内存错误
will throw a memory error once this list
物体变大了
object has grown so large that it
消耗所有可用内存。
consumes all available memory.
不管是无限循环还是崩溃，
Either way, whether it's an infinite loop or a crash,
这是规范允许的，因为你
that's permitted by the spec because you
如果你这么做就违反了先决条件。
violated the precondition if you're doing it.
现在也记住我们隐含的前提条件
Now remember also our implicit precondition
列表1和列表2必须是有效对象，不能为空。
that list one and list two must be valid objects, not null.
我们通常不说这个，因为事实上
We'll usually omit saying this because it's virtually always
需要对象引用。
required of object references.
这是另一个变异方法的例子。
Here's another example of a mutating method.
这是Sort，它需要一个字符串列表，没有前置条件，
This is Sort, it takes a list of strings, has no precondition,
它将列表按顺序排列，这样我的列表，
and it puts the list in sorted order so that list of i,
所以让我们列一张j的清单，我比j小。
so let's make a list of j for all i's less than j.
下面是一个方法的例子
And here's an example of a method that
不会改变它的论点。
does not mutate its argument.
两个小写，它接受字符串列表并返回
Two lower case that takes a list of strings and returns
一个新列表，其中该列表的每个元素
a new list, where each element of that list
是对应元素的小写版本
is the lower case version of the corresponding elements
输入列表的。
of the input list.
正如我们所说的，null是隐式不允许的
And just as we've said that null is implicitly disallowed
除非另有说明，我们
unless stated otherwise, we're also
使用不允许变异的惯例
going to use the convention that mutation is disallowed
除非另有说明。
unless stated otherwise.
所以这并不是说，即使你通过了
So this does not say, even though you're passing it
这里有一个可变的对象，它没有
a mutable object here, it does not
假设它会改变那个物体。
say it's going to mutate that object.
所以在没有描述突变的后条件的情况下
So in the absence of a post condition describing mutation
我们要求两个小写不改变它的输入列表。
we demand that two lower case not mutate its input list.